Effie Fowler | Software Engineer

linkedin.com/in/effiefowler | github.com/effie-fow

SKILLS

React, Node, Express, MySQL, Agile Development, APIs, Jest, User Authentication (JWT), Deployment (Heroku & Netlify), GitHub/GitFlow, Pair Programming, HTML, CSS, Sass, Photoshop, Google Workspace, Slack

PROJECTS

Full Stack Developer | Half Full Refills

SEP 2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

Half Full refills is a full-stack web application which I have taken a lot of joy in building, whilst sharpening the tools and industry-standard practices I have learnt during my BrainStation bootcamp.

Frontend Developer | Lloyds Bank 24 Hour Hackathon

SEP 2024, BRAINSTATION INDUSTRY PROJECT

Multidisciplinary hackathon providing opportunity to collaborate with UX Designers and Data Scientists.

PROFILE

I love web development because in it I have discovered a source of endless opportunities to satisfy my desire to learn, flex my creative muscles, and problem solve as an individual, as part of a team, and a global community.

As a software engineer, I draw from the skills I have developed at BrainStation, whilst harnessing a wide range of professional practices through my time as Communications & Fundraising Manager at a regional LGBT+ youth charity. I have worked enthusiastically and responsibly as a "one person department", whilst welcoming opportunities to collaborate with adjacent teams, stakeholders and service users. My suitability for this industry is found primarily in my patience, attention to detail and adaptability, which I have honed through a varied workload on both long-term projects and reactive, time-sensitive assignments alike. My excitement to continue my professional journey in software engineering stems from an eagerness to be a part of an ever-evolving industry, to continue learning, and to contribute to an organisation I am passionate about, as a valued member of your community.

EXPERIENCE

Communications & Fundraising Manager | Allsorts Youth Project

SEP 2019 - JUN 2024, BRIGHTON

- Managed, developed and delivered the charity's updated fundraising and communications strategy, which generated an increased annual income of 88% in 5 years.
- Rebranded Allsorts' visual and written identity, designing and implementing changes across public platforms.

Supervisor | Loading Brighton (Gaming Café) | MAR 2019 - SEP 2019 Supervisor | Zona Rosa (Mexican Restaurant) | APR 2018 - MAR 2019 English Teacher | EC Brighton (English Language School) | MAR 2018 - APR 2018 Barista / Service | Little Miss Piggies (Café) | JUL 2015 - NOV 2017

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering | JUL 2024 - OCT 2024, LONDON

University of Sussex | Bachelor of Arts in Music, 2:1 | SEP 2012 - JUN 2015, BRIGHTON